CASSONDRA REINSEL

Hayward, Ca 94541

Phone: (510) 938-3637 | Email: cassiereinsel@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/cassondra-reinsel-1a195840 | **Github:** github.com/creinsel

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with extensive experience in the education/public service industry. Recently earned a certificate in Full Stack Development through the UC Berkeley Extension program. Familiar with technologies such as Javascript, HTML, Node.js, React, Express, Handlebars, etc. With a background as a former educator, extremely efficient at meeting deadlines, thinking critically, and using creativity to complete work. Love learning from others in a collaborative environment and am passionate about creating web applications that are both functional and aesthetic.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technologies: Javascript, Jquery, Node.js, MySQL, Sequelize, React.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Firebase, CSS, Mocha, Cheerio, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML

PROJECTS

KyndCo | github.com/creinsel/KyndCo

- KyndCo is designed to encourage acts of kindness.
- Users have the ability to sign up for an account where they are given a list of "Kynd Acts" that they can complete for themselves, others or the world. Once the act is completed it will be graphed and listed on their "kyndline."
- For this project, created routes, controllers, select react components, password encryption and models.
- Built with React, Node, Express, MongoDb, Mongoose, BCrypt, Canvas.js, React-Bootstrap, Moment.js

Eat-Da-Burger | github.com/creinsel/burger | secret-plains-47747.herokuapp.com

- Eat-Da-Burger! is a restaurant app that lets users input the names of burgers they'd like to eat. Whenever a user submits a burger's name, the app will display the burger on the left side of the page
- Each burger in the waiting area also has a button with a fork and knife. When the user clicks it, the burger will move to the right side of the page to the Devoured table
- The app will store every burger in a database, whether devoured or not
- Built with MySql, PostgreSQL, Node, Express, Handlebars, Bootstrap

Friend-Finder | github.com/creinsel/friend-finder | hidden-lowlands-14815.herokuapp.com

- A compatibility-based "FriendFinder" application. This full-stack site takes in results from users' surveys, then compares their answers with those from other users. Upon submission of the survey, the app displays the name and picture of the user with the best overall match.

- Built with Node.js, Javascript. Bootstrap, Express

Train-Scheduler | github.com/creinsel/train-scheduler | creinsel.github.io/train-scheduler/

- A train schedule application that incorporates Firebase to host arrival and departure data. The app retrieves and manipulates this information with Moment.js. The website provides up-to-date information about various trains, namely their arrival times and how many minutes remain until they arrive at their station.
- Built with Firebase, Moment.js, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap

Tatt-It | github.com/jontruong/Project2 | young-lake-73302.herokuapp.com/

- An application designed to help users search for tattoo artists. Users also have the option to add artists to the application's database
- Created the html and api routes, in addition to the models for the MySql database and some portions of the front-end design
- Built with Node.js, Javascript. Jquery, Materialize, Express, Sequelize, MySql

EXPERIENCE

Academic Vocational Evaluator

Hayward Unified School District, Hayward

January 2019-present

track student progress in various HAS programs and submit data to the NRS in order to receive funding, import/export data between TopsPRO and ASAP, Sign in candidates via the Admissions Manager program on the Admin computer, troubleshoot when issues arise, communicate via phone and email with testing companies regarding various topics

Malabar House, Castro Valley, Ca

Child Care Worker/House Manager:

May 2017-present

Receive, provide care for and supervise youth (ages 8-17)that are brought to Malabar house by police officers in Alameda County, Provide activities to keep youth entertained while at facility, Regularly communicate with various counseling agencies regarding youth, complete various paperwork to compile a record for youth, maintain facility records

Aspire Public Schools, Golden State Prep, Oakland, Ca *Instructional Assistant SPED Department:*

February 2017- May

2017

Manage caseload of 15 student with Individualized Education Plans, Provide specialized academic instruction

Middle/High School Educator at Ka'u High School Hawaii Department of Education, Pahala, HI

July 2014-June 2016

Devised and executed lesson plans in 3 subjects, catering to secondary-level students diverse in age, ability, socioeconomic status, and ethnicity, Meticulously tracked student performance data to gauge effectiveness of lessons and teaching techniques, Oversaw and planned activities for student enrichment, including three field trips and fundraisers, As Lead Advisor for class of 2018, kept students on track for graduation by organizing class meetings and fundraising

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development: UC Berkeley Extension, Berkeley, California

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Arts: University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California